Lucas R. Stahl

Senior Developer Marketing Manager & Web Developer

Motivated professional with seventeen plus years of experience in digital marketing, business development and web programming. Skilled in managing projects from concept to completion, designing educational strategies and coaching individuals to success. Adaptable leader with an ability to work independently, creating effective presentations, and developing opportunities that further establish organizational goals.

Technical Skills

Certified Developer
HTML/CSS
JavaScript (Node, React, jQuery)
SQL (MySQL, MongoDB)

Google Analytics
Adobe (InDesign, Photoshop, Premiere)
Social Media
Content Management Systems

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Contentful | Remote

March 2021 – Present

Senior Developer Marketing Manager, Developer Relations Manager

- Built the developer marketing program, focused on community-led growth.
- Managed a team of developer advocates.
- Developer acquisition campaign management.
- Scaled developer discoverability through search engine optimization and content creation.
- Managed developer pathways to the product via website and educational material, aimed at enhancing the developer portal
 and documentation.
- Led the developer strategy for technical content blogs, knowledgebase articles and starters

HERE Technologies | Chicago, IL/Remote

November 2018 – March 2021

Developer Marketing Manager

- Executed scalable campaigns to drive growth in adoption of tools and APIs.
- Achieved 27% growth year-over-year in 2019.
- Managed strategic marketing growth initiatives for developers.
- Global campaign management for self-serve and paid plans driving developer growth.
- Implemented developer driven email campaigns and monthly developer newsletters.
- Directed input from key partners into marketing programs and integrated multi-channel campaigns (e.g., events, email, paid search, paid social, display, retargeting and content marketing).
- Website and content optimization, SEO strategy and CMS management of developer portal.

Northwestern Medicine | Chicago, IL

April 2012 – November 2018

Senior Marketing Specialist

- Managed both paid and organic social media tactics with high conversion success.
- Digital marketing lead for entire north region, focused on email marketing, web content/auditing and SEO.

Odyssey Hospice Care | Arlington Heights, IL | Account Executive
Vitas Innovative Hospice Care | Chicago, IL | Sales Representative
Physiotherapy Associates | Chicago, IL | Marketing Manager

November 2010 – April 2012 August 2009 – November 2010 December 2005 – August 2009

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development Northwestern University	2017 - 2018
Master of Arts in Communications: New Media and Marketing Southern New Hampshire University	2014 - 2017
Bachelor of Science in Communications and Media Studies Illinois State University	2001 - 2006